
24 
Name, Stand, Wohnort und hiesige 
Wohnung der angemeldeten Fremden: 
Uebertrag: 1736 
Abrahamson, Stefanie, Frau, mit Sohn, Berlin, Strandburg 2 
Altmann, Heinz, Oberprimaner, Stettin, Goldsried — — 
Angersbach, Rich., Direktor, mit Frau, Schöneberg, Strandburg 2 
Arnold, Gertrud, Frau, Wilmersdorf, Strandburg — — 1 
Altmann, Dr., Zahnarzt, Wilmersdorf, Nußbaum — — — 1 
Altvater, Theo Herrn., Diplom-Ingen., mit Frau, Steglitz, Mia 2 
Abrahamson, I., Arzt, mit Frau, Berlin, Excelsior — — — 2 
Assimakoputo, Dido, Student, Berlin, Margarete — — —r 
Autor, Dr., Arzt, mit Frau, Berlin, Luise —. — — — — 2 
Lach, Christian, Architekt, Charlottenburg, Haiderose —. — 1 
Bauer, Anna, Frau Oberstleutnant, Dresden, Dünenschloß — 1 
Becker, Mathilde, Ww., Schöneberg, Haiderose — — — 1 
Becker, Frieda, Frl. Dr., Schöneberg, Haiderose — — — 
Benz, Fritz, Ingen., mit Frau, Berlin, Friedensburg — — 2 
Bilz, Anton, Fabrikbesitzer, mit Farn., Berlin, Strandburg — 3 
Borger, Alfred, Kaufm., Berlin, Jester — — — — — 1 
Brandler, Sigmund, Kaufm., mit Sohn, Berlin, Jester — — 2 
Brasch, Martin, Kaufm., Charlottenburg, Strandburg —. — 1 
Bratt, Hermann, Kaufm., mit Frau, Charlottenburg, Goldfried 2 
Barmann, Hugo, Bankbeamter, Berlin, Vineta —. — — 1 
Boesner, Johanna, Frau, Berlin, Kaiser Wilhelm — — — 1 
Bosdorf, Franz, Kaufm., mit Frau, Potsdam, Vineta — — 2 
Bösel, Paul, Kaufm., mit Frau, Berlin, Vineta — — — 2 
Bumke, Erich, Dr., mit Frau, Berlin, Barbarossa — —. — 2 
Bachmann, Hans Wilhelm, Opernsänger, Stettin, Hubertus — 1 
Barbasch, Bruno, Arzt, mit Frau, Berlin, Schloß-Hotel — — 2 
Bartels, Walter, Kaufm., mit Frau, Berlin, Hubertus — — 2 
v Beyern, Gero, Landwirt, Kl. Benz (Pomm.), Hubertus — 1 
Bell, W., Major a. D., Steglitz, Hubertus — — — — — 1 
Bemb, Fritz, Syndikus, mit Frau u. Bed., Berlin, Dünenschloß 3 
Berger, Max, Kaufm., mit Frau, Berlin, Kaiser Wilhelm — 2 
Bessert, Johannes, Direktor, Tegel, Lunkewitz — — — — 1 
Böngan, Walter, cand. chem., Berlin, Seeschloß — — — 1 
Boretius, Marie, Frau Direktor, Berlin, Seeschloß — — — 1 
Boretius, Luise, Berlin, Seeschloß — — — — — — 1 
Born, Bruno, Dr., Zahnarzt, mit Frau, Berlin, Dünenschloß — 2 
Brasch, Leonhard, Kfm., mit Frau, Charlottenburg, Strandburg 2 
Briese, Amanda, Wilmersdorf, Excelsior — — — — — 1 
Brunnswig, Hermann, Fabrikbesitzer, Malchin, Möwe — — 1 
de Baer, Rosette, Gertrud und Meta, Berlin, Fresena — — 3 
Bartholm, Zahnarzt, mit Fam., Berlin, Waterkant — — — 3 
Berger, Kaufm., Berlin, Erlenschloß — — — — — — 1 
Bernhardt, Friedrich, Kausm., mit Frau, Stettin, Luise — — 2 
Bindel, Sally, Kaufm., mit Frau, Berlin, Barbarossa — — 2 
Bindel, Wilhelm, Kaufm., mit Frau, Berlin, Barbarossa — 2 
Bloch, Arthur, Dr., Rechtsanwalt, Berlin, Hohenstaufen — — 1 
Böhm, Heinrich, Kaufm., mit Frau, Stettin, Hohenstaufen — 2 
Brock, Isidor, Justizrat, mit Frau, Berlin, Waterkant — — 2 
Brock, Walter, Rechtskandidat, Berlin, Waterkant —. — — 1 
Bromberg, Kurt, Schriftsteller, Berlin, Luise — — — — 1 
Voedewig, Adolf, Kfm., mit Fam. u. Bed., Hamburg, Steinberg 4 
Crooke, I., Ingen., Berlin, Hubertus — — — — — 1 
Lohn, Heinz, Oberprimaner, Stettin, Goldfried — — — 1 
Carell, Carl, Bankier, mit Fam., Berlin, Jester — — — 3 
Conrad, Hans, Dr. med., pr. Arzt, m. Fr., Steglitz, Goldfried 2 
Citron, San.-Rat, Charlottenburg, Barbarossa — — — 1 
Cramer, Ernst, Kaufm., mit Frau, Berlin, Seeschloh — — 2 
Destler, Felix, Kaufm., Berlin, Jester — — — — — 1 
Derz, Erich, Diplom-Ingen., mit Frau, Wilmersdorf, Vineta 2 
Dey, Bernhard, Prokurist, Berlin, Agnes — —, — — 
Delius, Fritz und Kurt, Prenzlau, Martha-Elsehaus — — 
Dethnar, H., Bankbeamter, mit Frau, Berlin, Agnes — — 
Diedrich, Max, Kaufm., mit Frau, Greifswald, Excelsior — 2 
Dierdorf, Hans, Kaufm., Berlin, Schloß-Hotel — — — 1 
Diern, Walter, Referendar, Stettin, Hubertus — — — — 1 
Digalski, Kurt, Kaufm., Berlin, Hubertus — — — — 1 
Dörre, Otto, Kaufm., mit Frau, Berlin, Hubertus — — — 2 
Doll, Andreas, Architekt, mit Frau, Berlin, Strandburg — — 2 
Daase, Martin, Rechtsanw. u. Notar, mit Frau, Fürstenwalde, 
Agnes — — — — — — —. — — — — 2 
Elermann, Hans, Bankbeamter, Charlottenburg, Goldfried — 1 
Eisenstaedt, Wilhelm, Kaufm., mit Frau, Stettin, Mia — — 2 
Ebbert, E., Arzt, mit Frau, Pankow, Haiderose — —. — 2 
Eilrich, Paul, Malermstr., mit Fam., Berlin, Schloß-Hotel — 3 
Eisfeld, Walter, Prokurist, mit Frau, Lankwitz, Hubertus — 2 
Eisinger, Arpad, Bücherrevisor, mit Frau, Berlin, Excelsior — 2 
Freund, Erwin, Dr., Arzt, mit Frau, Südende, Strandburg — 2 
Friedemann, Berthold, Kaufm., Charlottenburg, Vineta — — 1 
Friese, Günter, Schüler, Berlin, Vineta — — — — — 
Falkenberg, Otto, Kaufm., mit Frau, Berlin, Dllnenschloß — 2 
Fesch, Rudolf, Kapellmeister, mit Frau, Halensee, Agnes — 2 
Fickert, Rudolf, Techniker, Berlin, Moltkestr. 17 — — — 1 
Fischer, Eduard, Prokurist, mit Fam., Stettin, Dünenschloß — 7 
Fork, Anna, Berlin, Agnes — — —, — — — — 1 
Fraenkel, Manfred, Dr., Arzt, m. Fr., Charlottenburg, Tip Top 2 
Fränkel, Richard, Dr., Kammergerichtsrat, Wilmersdorf, Gretel 1 
Fuchs, Paul, Dr., Sanitätsrat, mit Tochter, Berlin, Tip Top — 2 
Finkelstein, Betty, Frl. Dr., Berlin, Seeblick — — — — 1 
Gehlert, Hans, Berlin, Hohenstaufen — — — — — 1 
Gerber, Waldemar, Zeitungsverl., mit Frau und Chauffeur, 
Charlottenburg, Waterkant —&gt; -— — — — — 3 
Giese, Margarete, Geschäftsinhaberin, Stettin, Tip Top — 1 
Gollnick, Karl, Verlagsdir., mit Fr., Tempelhof, Hohenstaufen 2 
Gollnick, Kurt, Rechtsanwalt, mit Frau, Berlin, Hohenstaufen 2 
Gloeckner, Lisa, Charlottenburg, Dünenschloß — — — — 1 
Ganschow, Marie, Frau, m. F., Königsberg i. M., Barbarossa 4 
Gernhardt, Hugo,. Drogist, Spandau, Vineta — — — — 1 
Goldschmidt, Robert, Diplom-Ingen., Berlin, Barbarossa — 1 
Grambow, Hans Joachim, Berlin, Wilhelmsruh — —&gt; — 
v. Grieken, Walter, Reg.-Oberinsp.,- Berlin, Vineta — —1 
Gellhaar, Herbert, Kaufm., Stargard i. P., Irmela —, — — 1 
Gerlach, Martha, Frl., Berlin, Seeschloß — — — — 1 
Giesen, Karl, Syndikus, mit Frau, Berlin, Excelsior — — 2 
Gloeckner, Heinr., Diplom-Ingen., Charlottenburg, Dünenschloß 1 
Goetschel, Käte, Stettin, Excelsior — — — — — — 1 
Golan, Frau, Stettin, Excelsior — — — — — — 1 
Golan, Fräulein, Stettin, Excelsior — — — — — 1 
Goldberg, W., Diplom-Ingen., Berlin, Hubertus — —, — 1 
Groll, Fr., Direktor, mit Fam., Berlin, Möwe — — 
Grünewald, Albert, Kaufm., mit Fam., Stettin, Agnes — — 3 
Gabriel, Gertrud und Agnes, Schneidemühl, Gretel — — 2 
Galeen, Henrik, Regisseur, Charlottenburg, Waterkant — — 1 
Herrmann, Heinz, Wilmersdorf, Wartburg — — — — 
Haller, Paul, Direktor a. Konservatorium, Berlin, Hubertus — 1 
Hammermeister, Emmi, Geschäftsinhaberin, Berlin, Midgard 1 
Hauser, Siegfried, Kaufm., Berlin, Dünenschloß — — — 1 
Hardt, Robert, Kaufm., mit Frau, Schöneberg, Goldfried — 2 
Heinemann, Paul, Apotheker, Berlin, Barbarossa — — — 1 
Hauptmann, Karl, Kaufm., mit Sohn und Hausdame, Berlin, 
Rolandseck — — — — — —. —. — — — 3 
Haas, Hans Erich, Dr. med., Berlin, Excelsior —. — — — 1 
Haas, Lisel, Berlin, Excelsior — — — — — — — 1 
Haller, Max, Direktor a. Konservatorium, Berlin, Hubertus — 1 
Happel, Clara, Frau, Berlin, Hubertus — — — — — 1 
Harmann, Alfred, Fabrikant, mit Frau, Berlin, Gerichtslaube 2 
Haß, Reinhard, Dr., Regierungsrat, m. Frau, Berlin, Haiderose 2 
Hanfs, Alfr., Rechtsanw., mit F. u. Bed., Stettin, Friedensburg 6 
Hecht, Alma, Frl., Lieplow, Seeschloß — — — — — 1 
Heimann, Wilhelm, Kaufm., mit Frau, Stettin, Friedensburg 2 
Heitmann, Hermann, Ingen., mit Fam., Stettin, Haiderose — 3 
Herrmann, Wilhelm, Kaufm., mit Frau, Berlin, Möwe — — 2 
Hoffmann, Fritz, Kaufm., mit Fam., Stettin, Haiderose — — 3 
Hogrefe, Otto, Stettin, Auguste Viktoria — — — — — 1 
Hoitzer, Gerhard, Kaufm., mit Fam., Stettin, Haiderose — — 4 
Hüther, Franziska, Stettin, Agnes — — — — — — 1 
Herold, Martha, Konrektorin, Berlin, Kaiser Wilhelm — — 1 
Heller v. Lellenberg, A., Frau, mit Chauffeur, Berlin, Möwe 2