
Nr. 8. 
Name, Stand, Wohnort und hiesige Wohnung der angekonnnenen Fremden. 
Donnerstag, den 8. Juli 1915. 
Müller, Eugen Franz, Kaufm., Cöpenick-Berlin, Radtke, Lotseustr. 57 1 
Müller, Lucie, Frl., Gr. Lichterfelde, Oberhof, Gr. Kirchenstr. 62b — 1 
Mittelstaedt, Fran Oberstleutnant, mit Bed., Berlin-Friedenau, Haus 
Elisabeth — — — — — — — — —- — — — 2 
Meißner, Mar, Mechaniker, Berlin-Steglitz, Oehlkes Gasth. — — 1 
Manns, Margarete, Frau Kanfm., mit Fam. u. Bed., Berlin, Steffen 6 
Miersch, Amalie Nelly, Lehrerin, Berlin, Annaburg — — — — 1 
Matz, Frida, Frl., Stettin, Prinz Heinrich — — — — — — 1 
Moldenhauer, Margarete, Frl., Charlottenburg, Roßmann, Bedastr. 3 1 
Münch, Elly, Frl., Natzmersdorf (P.h Strandpalast — — — — 1 
Mälzer, Magdalene, Kind.rpflegeschwester, Lendhardt i. Sa., Martha- 
Elsehaus — — — — — — — — — — — — 1 
Müller, Gerd, Schüler, Grnnewald-Berlin, Martha-Elsehaus — — 1 
Miles, Kurt, Schüler, Potsdam, Meihos, Gr. Kirchenstr. 9/10 — — 1 
Meycrheim, Else, Fran, Potsdam, Preußenhof — — — — — 1 
Mielk, Alfred, Ingen., Berlin, Preußenhof — — — — — — 1 
Meßner, Wilhelm, Rittergutsbesitzer, m. Fam. n. Bed., Labow b. Pyritz, 
Fremdenheim Seeschloß — — — — — — — — — 4 
Maeder, Marie, Frau Privatiere, Dresden, Ostsee-Gasth. — — — 1 
Maliska, Marie, Frau, Schöneberg b. Berlin, Melanie — — — 1 
Metscher, Frida, Frau, mit Tochter, Berlin-Schöneberg, Vielliebchen — 2 
Micklisch, Paul, Fabrikant, Berlin, Azurea — — — — — — 1 
Miethe, Elsa, Frau, Berlin, Krasucki — — — — — — — 1 
Mollenhaner, Ick-. mack., mit Fam. u. Bed., Zehlendorf, Barbarossa — 3 
Moritz, Gertrud, Frl., Pyritz, Köller, Waldstr. 5 — — — — — 1 
Müller, Frida, Frau Major, Godesberg a. Rh., Rode, Moltkestr. 23 — 1 
Müller, Martha, Fran, mit Sohn, Berlin, Fortuna — — — — 2 
Mannebeck, Ewald, Kanfm., Berlin, Jeschkes Gasth. — — — — 1 
Maaß, Earl, Kanfm., mit Frau, Stettin, Prinz Heinrich — — — 2 
Meden, August, Kaufm., Dresden, Preußeuhof — — — — — 1 
Maeder, Heinz, Schüler, Berlin, Martha-Elsehaus — — — — 1 
May, Dipl.-Ingen., Charlottenburg, Dresdener Hof — — — — 1 
Mecklenburg, Charlotte, Schülerin, Lichtenberg-Berlin, Waldfrieden — 1 
Meyer, Klara, Frau, mit Farn., Berlin-Tegel, Hans Wanda — — 3 
Meyer, Otto und Gerhard, Gebr., Lekvw, Emma Louise — — — 2 
Meißner, Margarete, Frau Hauptmann, mit Tochter, Charlottenburg, 
Glückauf — — — — — — — — — — — 2 
Meschkat, F., Frau, mit Sohn, Berlin, Moratz, ^chulstr. 12 — — — 2 
Mönch, Georg, Kaufm., mit Fam., Altdamm, Hubertus — — — 3 
Müller, Margarete, Lehrerin, Frankfurt a. M., Müller, Roonstr. 1 — 1 
Nir, Elisabeth, Stütze, Berlin-Lichtenberg, Maria-Theresia — — 1 
Nathusius, Frau Rittmeister, mit Fam. u. Bed., Cöln, Ostsee-Gasth — 5 
Neumann, Anna, Frau, mit Tochter, Labes, Louise — — — — 2 
Nagel, Margarete, Frau Kaufm., mit Sohn, Berlin, Schiffmann — 2 
Naschelsky, Albert, Kaufm., Malmö, Ostsee-Gasth. — — — — 1 
Neumann, Elsa, Frau Kaufm., mit Sohn u. Bed., Wilmersdorf, Schulz 4 
Niepolinski, Günter und Herbert, Gebrüder, Berlin, Kinderpflegeheim 2 
Nolte, Margarete, Frau, Altdamm, Krüger, Moltkestr. 21 — — 1 
Neugebauer, Frida, Frau, mit Sohn, Berlin, Leske, Friedenstr. 11 — 2 
Neuhahn, Herm., Fabrikant, Berlin, Eberts Straudkonditorei — — 1 
Neumann, Aug., Berlin, Ella — — — — — — — — — 1 
Neumann, Emma' Frau, Berlin, Ella — — — — — — — 1 
Nimz, Emil, 1b-., Festungs-Garnisonspfarrer, Grandenz, Nimz, Färber 
straße 15 — — — — — — — — — — — — 1 
Nimz, Herbert, Kadett, Köslin, Nimz, Färberstr. 15 — — — — 1 
Ollendorf, Luise, Kind, Stettin, Jesters Strandkonditorei — — — 1 
Oppmann, Richard, Kaufm., Hamburg, Preußenhof — — — — 1 
Oehme, Irmgard, Schülerin, Potsdam, Martha-Elfehaus — —' — 1 
Oehme, Marie, Frau Rittergutsbesitzer, Potsdam, Strandpalast — 1 
Palm, Auguste, Frl., Eberswalde, Klnth, Maaßnerstr. 6 — — — 1 
Peters, Heinrich, Direktor, Berlin, Schloß am Meer — — — — 1 
Pick, Siegmund, Kaufm., Berlin, Schmidts Gasth. — — — — 1 
Papke, Carl, Kaufm., Stettin, Wilhelma — — — — — — 1 
Peisker, Elise, Frau Landgerichtsrat, Dr. sm-., m. Fam. u. Bed., Berlin- 
Wilmersdorf, Wilhelma — — — — — — — — 5 
Pfannenbecker, Elise, Frail, Stettin, Nußbaum — — — — — 1 
v. Poniet, E., Hauptmann, ? Haus Babette — — — — 1 
Pottlitz, Käte, Frl., Lübeck, Gosch, Admiralstr. — — — — — 1 
Pon Prondzinski, Margarete, Frl., Berlin-Treptow, Knuth, Grenzstr. 3 1 
Patzelt, Gerhard, Schüler, Kottbus, Martha-Elsehaus — — — — 1 
Petrich, Werner, Schüler, Spremberg, Martha-Elsehaus — — — 1 
Paukan, Else, Frau Kammergerichtsrat, mit Fam., Berlin, Azurea — 3 
Prenzlau, Max, Kaufm., Berlin, Preußeuhof — — — — — — 1 
Paunewitz, Else, Schülerin, Berlin, Auf der Düue — — — — 1 
Pauten, Gertrud, Musiklehrerin, Berlin, Aegir — — — — — 1 
Patzelt, Frau, mit Tochter, Stettin, Ostsee-Sanatorium — — — 2 
Pehl, Walter, Schauspieler, Königsberg, Beutlage, Königsstr. 17 — 1 
Pfeffermann, Gertrud, Lotte und Ruth, Frl. Geschw., Charlottenburg, 
Herkules — — — — — — — — — — — — 3 
Pfennigwerth, Käte, Fran Fabrikbesitzer, mit Fam. n. Bed., Berlin, 
Air de Waterkant — — — — — — — — — — 3 
Pflüger, Kathr., Frau Fabrikbesitzer, mit Sohn u. Begleiterin, Berlin, 
Ostsee-Gasth. — — — — — — — — — — — 3 
Pricken, Karl, Vizefeldwebel, mit Frau, Prenzlau, Park-Gasth. — — 2 
Prochnow, Eva, Schülerin, Berlin, Maritima — — — — — 1 
Plato, Will), Kanfm., Bad Harzbnrg, Jeschkes Gasth. — — — — 1 
Pichlinger, Hermann, Kanfm., mit Fam., Stettin, Preußeuhof — — 3 
Pankow, Luise, Frau, Stettin, Sellin, Kirchplatz 10 — — — — 1 
Papke, Erna, Frau, Stettin, Bieber, Gr. Kirchenstr. 92 — — — 1 
Papke, Gertrud, Frau, mit Tochter, Stettin, Bieber, Gr. Kirchenstr. 92 2 
Pittschan, Lilly, Frl., Charlottenburg, Käte — — — — — — 1 
Prenß, Lina, Frau, mit Fam., Weißensee b. Berlin, Preuß, Steinbrück- 
straße 4 — — — — — — — — — — — — 3 
Prigau, Marg., Frau, Berlin, Hübner — — — — — — — 1 
Raithel, Fritz, Kaufm., Berlin, Herta — — — — — — — 1 
Rösener, Geh. Baurat, Stettin, Walfisch — — — — — — — 1 
Ramin, Lucie, Frau Direktor, mit Kiud u. Bed., Schmargendorf, Haus 
Goldfried — — — — — — — — — — — — 3 
Richter, Hans, Kaufm., Berlin, Haus Bernhard — — — — — 1 
Rösler, Fritz, Schüler, Berlin-Schöneberg, Martha-Elsehaus — — 1 
Riepe, Amalie, Frau Bezirksrichter, mit Sohn, Reichenberg in Böhmen, 
Viktoria-Gasth. — — — — — — — — — — — 2 
Reinhold, Alpine, Rentiere, Lambau i. Schl., Fußhauer, Färberstr. 16 1 
Reuther, Anna, Frl., Berlin, Klara — — — — — — — — 1 
Ringer, Albert, Kaufm., Berlin, Ella — — — — — — — 1 
Robitschek, Margarete, Frau Kaufm., Wilmersdorf, Strandburg" — 1 
Roggenstroh, Elisabeth, Frau Lehrer, mit Fam., Steglitz, Vieth, Swine 
straße 13 — — — — — — — — — — — — 3 
Rosenau, Simon, Kaufm., Nördlingen, Wiedemann, Krausestr. 9 — 1 
Rund, Walter, Stralsund, Schmücke, Friedenstr. 4 — — — — 1 
Rocke, Fritz, Schüler, Berlin, Pasch, Fürberstr. 13 — — — — 1 
Roch, Otto, Offizierstellvertreter, Greifswald, Preußenhof — — — 1 
Runge, Leutnant, mit Frau, Stettin, Preußenhof — — — — — 1 
Rubin, Felix, Kanfm., Wreschen i. P., Preußeuhof — — — — 1 
Rosenthal, Fritz, Kaufm., Berlin, Prenßenhof -— — — — — — 1 
Rubinstein, Artur, Ist-., Spezialarzt, mit Fam. u. Bed., Berlin- 
Wilmersdorff, Auf der Düne — — — — — — — 5 
Razel, Artur, Oberlehrer, mit Frau, Stettin, Schloß Hohenzollern — 2 
Rehmke, Hans, Leutnant d. R., Greifswald, Fremdenheim Seeschloß — 1 
Retschlag, Herwart, Apothekenbesitzer, mit Fran, Berlin, Dünenschloß 2 
Robitschek, Artur, Kaufm., Wilmersdorf, Strandburg — — — — 1 
Rosing, Bernhard, Ick-., Geh. Regierungsrat, m. Fam., Berlin, Friedens 
burg — — — — —- — —. — — — — — —&gt;3 
Rohs, Martha, Priv., Hohen-Neuendorf, Zieger, Moltkestr. 24 — — 1 
Rosenberg, Max, Kaufm., Berlin-Neukölln, Fürst Bismarck — — 1 
Roloff, Edmund, Hauptmann, Posen, Prenßenhof — — — — 1 
Rauh, Gertrud, Frau Baumeister, mit Fam., Berlin, Nafade — — 3 
Radicke, Martha, Frl., Eberswalde, Dewischeit, Gartenstr. 16 — — 1 
Reibach, Auguste, Frau, mit Tochter, Berlin, Erlenschloß — — — 2 
Reichest, Ernst, Rentier, mit Fam., Potsdam, Schulz, Königsstr. 15 3 
Reiche, Gerhard, Schüler, Berlin, Henke, Fischerstr. 22 — — — 1 
Reimers, Hans, 1st-, jur., Bürgermeister, mit Frau, Wolgast i. Pomm., 
Goldfried — — — — — — — — — — — — 2 
Richard, Frau Rentiere, Wriezen, Seerings Gasth. — — — — — 1 
Richard, Willy, Rendant, Wriezen, Seerings Gasth. — — — — 1 
Richter, Martha, Geschäftsleiterin, Potsdam, Richter, Steinbrückstr. 5 1 
Rocke, Else, Frau, nut Sohn, Berlin, Pasch, Färberstr. 13 — — — 2 
Rölbe, Johannes, Postsekretär, Friedrichshagen, Herta — — — — 1 
Rosengreen, Maria, Lehrerin, Seesen a. H., Rosengreen, Moltkestr. 9 — 1 
Rothschild, Alfred, Du. muck., Sanitätsrat, Berlin, Walfisch — — 1 
Runge, Wilhelm, Leutnant, m. Fran, Wiesbaden, Richter, Friedenstr. 5 2 
Sommer, Gertrud, Privatiere, Charlottenburg, Splendid — — — 1 
Sarsen, Ellen, Kgl. Sängerin, Berlin, Düncnschloß — — — — 1 
Simonson, Alice, Schülerin, Berlin, Martha-Elsehaus — — — — 1 
Seydel, Ernst, Apotheker, Crimmitschau i. S., Hohenstaufen — — 1 
Solger, Lina, Frau Rentiere, Charlottenburg, An de Waterkant — — 1 
Selbiger, Heinrich, Kaufm., Berlin, Preußenhof — — — — — 1 
Simon, Louis, Kaufm., Güstrow, Preußeuhof — — — — — 1 
Suckow, Albiu, Versicherungs-Oberinspektor, mit Frau, Dresden, Lotte 2 
Salfner, Karl, Direktor, mit Fam., Berlin, An de Waterkant — — 4 
Sasse, Emmy und Marie, Frl. Geschw., Charlottenburg, Barbarossa — 2 
Sawade, Paul, Fabrikbesitzer, Züllichan, Strandburg — — — — 1 
Setzl, Hails, Kaufm., Stettin, Walfifch — — — — — — — 1 
Syben, Josefine, Frl., Berlin-Schöneberg, Greif — — — — — 1 
Saklikower, Rudolf, Kaufm., Berlin, Berolina — — — — — 1 
Sellinger, Armin, Schüler, Berlin, Jacoby, Königsstr. 17 — — — 1 
Sorg, Elisabeth, Frl., Breslau, Haus Wanda — — — — — 1 
Schmidt, Carl, Bankdirektor, mit Frau, Charlottenburg, Nußbaum"— 2 
Schelnaak, Frau Kaufm., Berlin, Preußenhof — — — — — 1 
Schermann, Selma, Frau Doktor, Rechtsanwalt, Berlin, Strandburg 1 
Schloter, Margarete, Priv., Bayreuth, Herta — — — — — — 1 
Schmok, Alex, Offizierstellvertreter, Berlin, Gasth. Westend — — 1 
Schrnok, Martha, Frl., Berlin, Gasth. Westcnd — — — — — 1 
Schwerdtfeger, Richard, Pfarrer, mit Töchtern, Colmar, Seestern — 3 
Schönlank, Ellie, Frau, mit Fam. u. Bed., Berlin, Waldfrieden — — 5 
Schmidt, Josefa, Frau Fabrikbesitzer, m. Fam. u. Bed., Potsdam, Schloß 
Hohenzollern — — — — — — — — — — — 4 
Schmidt, Margarete, Frau, Berlin-Steglitz, Arminius — — — — 1 
Schmidt, Walter, lick. mack., Spezialarzt, Allenstein, Am Meer — — 1 
Schob, Melanie, Frau Oberstleutnant, mit Tochter, Stettin, Nußbaum 2 
Schob, Otto, Kaufm, mit Fann, Schöneberg, Strandburg — — — 3 
Schönwald, Max, Kaufnr., mit Sohn, Berlin, Elisabeth — — — 2 
Schelm, Erna, Frl., Berlin-Wilmersdorf, Du. Müller, Wasserstr. 3 — 1 
Schütz, Frida, Frl., Burg b. Magdeburg, Neptun — — — — — 1 
Schering, Herbert, Schüler, Grunewald b. Berlin, Martha-Elsehaus — 1 
Schnoeck l, Herbert, Schüler, Charlottenburg, Martha-Elsehaus — — 1 
Schubert, Ernst, Schiller, Zittau, Martha-Elsehaus — — — — 1 
Schmigalla, Paul, Direktor, nut Fam. u. Bed., Berlin-Friedenau, Haus 
Freia — — — — — — — — — — — — — 4 
Schünemann, Anni, Kind, Charlottenburg, Klein, Moltkestr. 25 — — 1 
Schottländer, Bonslau, Drei Kronen — — — — — — — 1 
Stoebe, Casimir, Prokurist, Posen, Pension Kurpark — — — — 1