
Jarosch, Stephanie, mit Sohn, Charlottenburg, Bikloria Luise 2 
John, Wilhelm, Kreis Oberinsp., m. Fam., Nauen, Lotsenstr. 11 4 
Jonas, Fritz, mit Frau, Stettin, Gr. Kirchenstr. 89 — — 2 
Jonas, Walter, mit Frau, Berlin, Else — — — — 2 
Jungnickel, Elsa, Kinderfräulein, mit Kindern Blümel, Neusatz, 
Bedastr. 1 — — — — — — — — — — 3 
Juppe, Frieda, Glogau, Haus am Kurpark — — — — 1 
Jacoby, Gerhard, Kaufm., mit Begl., Belgard, Preutzenhof — 2 
Jacoby, Heinz, Kaufm., Berlin, Schmidts Hotel — — — 1 
Kallwaß, Irmgard, Stettin, Christliches Hospiz — — — 1 
Kambodt, Kurt, Apotheker, mit Fam., Frankfurt a. O., Lotsen- 
straße 52 — — — — — — — — — — 3 
Karger, James, Kaufm., Berlin-Wilmersdorf, Jester — — 1 
Karger, Franz, Kaufm., mit Frau, Charlottenburg, Wiesb. Hof 2 
Kasch, Richard, Kaufm., mit Frau, Cottbus, Waldschlotz — — 2 
Katz, Erna, Frau, mit Fam., Berlin, Waldblick — — — 3 
Keil, Alf., Pol.-Oberwachtm., Berlin Wilmersdorf, Gartenstr. 30 1 
Kesten, Johanna, Stettin, Neueste. 62 — — — — — 1 
Kländer, Carl, Berlin, Färberstr. 16u — — — — — 1 
Klappowitz, A., Kaufm., mit Frau, Stettin, Silesia — — — 2 
Klut, H., Dr., Prof., m. Fam., Brl.-Lichterfelde, Hartigstr. 16 3 
Knoll, Gertrud, mit Familie, Charlottenburg, Christl. Hospiz 3 
Knoll, Olga, Frau, mit Familie, Prag, Azurea — — — 3 
Kocky, A., Vikar, Schneidemühl, Hubertus — — — — 1 
König, Gustav, Reisender, mit Fam., Berlin, Neuestr. 35 — 3 
Koeppen, Heinrich, ? Lotsenstr. 10 — — — — — 1 
Korbs, Alfred, Dr. phil., mit Fam., Aue i. Erzgeb., Eden — 3 
Koesen, Andreas, Jng., mit Frau, Berlin, Christl. Hospiz — 2 
Korn, Clara, Frau, Stettin, Secschlotz — — — — — 1 
Korschaun, Heinz, Dr., Ingen., mit Frau, Essen, Strandpalast 2 
Kotacka, Marie, Verkäuferin, Wiesbaden, Wiesbadener Hof — 1 
von Krause, Boris, Kausm., Strassburg, Heysestr. 13 — — 1 
Krause, Gerhard, Berlin, Park-Hotel — — — — — — 1 
Kremser, Alfred, Berlin, Hindersinstr. 1 — — — — — 1 
Kroker, Gerda, Berlin, Park-Hotel — — — — — - 1 
Krüger, Helene, Frau, mit Tochter, Stettin, Clara — — — 2 
Kümme, Ludwig, mit Fam., Berlin-Steglitz, Wiesbadener Hof 3 
Kasten, Ernst, Dentist, mit Frau, Hannover, Jeschkes Hotel — 2 
Krafft, Otto, Kaufm., mit Frau, Potsdam, Jeschkes Hotel — 2 
Kuhlmann, Lotte, Frau, Berlin, Schmidts Hotel — — — 1 
Kitzinger, Hedwig, mit Tochter, Berlin-Dahlem, Jeschkes Hotel 2 
Kaiser, Carl, Kaufm., mit Frau, Stettin, Baltischer Hof 2 
Klemmd, Willi, Reisender, mit Frau, Dresden, Europäischer Hof 2 
Kolke, Th., Betriebsleiter, mit Frau, Offenbach, Baltischer Hof 2 
Kranz, Erich, Kaufm., Berlin, Baltischer Hof — — — 1 
Krause, Walter, Kaufm., Bornholm-Sandvig, Central-Hotel 1 
Kredewahn, Fedor, Kaufm., Warschau, Central-Hotel — — 1 
Krohn, Hans, Kaufm., Königsberg, Central-Hotel — — — 1 
Kuntzemüller, Ruth, Graphikerin, Leipzig, Baltischer Hof — 1 
Labensteiner, Grete, Nürnberg, Wiesbadener Hof — — — 1 
Lachmann, Kurt, Techniker, Berlin, Christl. Hospiz - — — 1 
von Lange, Hans Ulrich, Lehrer, Berlin, Auguste Viktoria — 1 
Lankowsky, Gertrud, Assistentin, Memel, Christl. Hospiz — 1 
Lappe, Marg., Arztfrau, mit Kindern, Breslau, Haiderose — 3 
Lauterbach, Rudolf, Kfm., mit Frau, Berlin-Steglitz, Barbarossa 2 
Leddin, Charlotte, Frau, mit Sohn, Jatznick, Karlsruherstr. 13 2 
Lehmann, Kurt, Buchhalter, Merseburg, Wiesbadener Hof — 1 
Lemke, Elvi, Buchenwalde, Gadebuschstr. 12 - — — - 1 
Lemme, Walter, Rathenow, Krausestr. 2 — — — — — 1 
Lippoldt, Dora, Frau, mit Sohn, Gehren i. Thür., Lotsenstr. 22 2 
Lüder, Marg., Kontoristin, Neuköln, Lotsenstr. 4Ü — — — 1 
Lukas, Else, Witwe, mit Sohn, Berlin, Wiesbadener Hos 2 
Lösener, Alb., Werkmstr., mit Fam., Oranienburg, Schmidts H. 5 
Landgraf, Hellmuth, Kaufm., mit Frau, Berlin-Halensee, Jeschke 2 
Leverenz, Marg., Lehrerin, Charlottenburg, Schmidts Hotel 1 
Lindner, Frieda, Berlin, Ostsee-Kurheim — — — — — 1 
Lange, Alfred, Berlin, Ostsee-Kurheim — — — — — 1 
Loppe, Wilhelm, Schabowitz i. Schl., Goldener Hirsch — — 1 
Leske, Mirka, Kontoristin, Berlin, Moltkestr. 23 — — — 1 
i/üer «Hie ///a«/»/ &lt;7// ru eZ/rem l s'/r/ztt/Ac-n. 
§Zc&gt;§ZZlr kmumke/r. — 
vsvll-v^kro&lt; 
8c«Ol&lt;Ol.^oc * p»^l.i^kbl R 
Magnus, Walli, Kalkberge, Gadebuschstr. 5 — — — 1 
Mayer, Herbert, Kandidat, Berlin, Christl. Hospiz — — 1 
Maennel, Amandes, Kaufm., mit Frau, Dresden. Wiesbad. Hof 2 
Manisch, Friedel, Stettin, Christl. Hospiz — — — 1 
Matysek, Hans, Kaufm., Loddin, Färberstr. 4 — — — — 1 
Meinickc, Herm, Werkinsp., m. Fr., Grube Erika, Wiesb. Hof 2 
Meyer, Walter, Kaufm., mit Frau, Berlin, Frieda — — 2 
Meier, Käte, Dr., Charlottenburg, Reinke — — — — 1 
Meer, Siegmund, Fabrikdirektor, Leipzig, Steffen — — 1 
Meer, Marg., Frau, Leipzig, Steffen - — — — — 1 
Moser, Franz, techn. Angest., mit Sohn, Berlin, Bollwerk 31 2 
Mühlstoff, Elfr., Frau, m. Sohn, Brl.-Schöneberg, Bedastr. 11 2 
Müller, H., Frau, mit Sohn, Elgersburg, Strandburg — — 2 
Müller, Karl, Werkmeister, mit Frau, Berlin, Latsenstr. 52 — 2 
Merschmann, Will)., Obersekretär, mit Frau, ? Lotsenstr. 10 2 
Mueller, Claus, Dr. med., mit Sohn, Breslau, Preutzenhof — 2 
Müller, Martha, Hotelbes., Auerbach, Preutzenhof — — — 1 
Meybacher, Siegsr., Chemiker, Oranienburg, Jeschkes Hotel 1 
Möller, Heinrich, Berlin, Ostsee-Kurheim — — — — — 1 
Mcrtensen, Wilhelm, Direktor, mit Frau, Berlin, Preutzenhof 2 
Münchhofs, Gustav, Jng., Berlin, Baltischer Hos — — — 1 
Nasthal, Hilde, Memel, Mia — — — — — — — 1 
Neblung, Karl, Prokurist, mit Fam., Erfurt, Wiesbadener Hof 3 
Neumann, Elisabeth, Frau, Memel, Christl. Hospiz — — 1 
Neumann, Lisa, Propagandistin, Stettin, Seeschlotz — — 1 
Neumann, M., Kaufm., mit Frau, Stettin, Lotsenstr. 52 — — 2 
von Nietzen, Eugen, Jng., Berlin-Schöneberg, Lotsenstr. 60 — 1 
Nims, Herbert, Rathenow, Krausestr. 2 — — — — — 1 
Nossek, Ruth, Berlin, Tip Top — — — — — — — 1 
Noak, Emilie, Witwe, mit Tochter, Rathenow, Hartigstr. 15 — 2 
Nothmann, Günther, Kaufm., Chemnitz, Ursula — — — 1 
Nave, Charlotte, Berlin, Ostsee-Kurheim — — »— — — 1