
Name, Stand, Wohnort und hiesige Wohnung der angemeldetcn Fremden: 
Uebertrag 13 612 
Anton, Max,' Kaufm., mit Frau, Wiesbadener Hof — — 2 
von Arnim, Harald, Referendar, Burow b. Menz, Schwer. Hof 1 
Alex, Elisabeth, Berlin, Pommernhaus — — — — — 1 
Altmann, Gerd, Schüler, Weihensee, Wald u. See — — — 1 
Amberg, Th., Kaufm., ? Excelsior — — — — 1 
Ankermann, Eharlotte, mit Kind, Königsberg, Lotsenstr. 30 — 2 
Arnfeld, Julius, Kaufm., mit Fam., Fürstenwalde, Atlantic — 3 
Adamski, Marg., Frau, mit Kind u. Bed., Berlin, Neuestr. 26 3 
Baade, Gustav, Stadtinsp., mit Fam., Nowawes, Heysestr. 1 — 3 
Baeskow, Alfred, Ober-Jng., mit Fam., Essen a. R., Steinberg 3 
Berndt, Anna, Frau, mit Tochter, Stettin, Herrenbadstr. 8 — 2 
Brendel, Marie, Ww., Breslau, Melanie — — .— — — 1 
Bruchlow, F., Kaufm., mit Frau, Eberswalde, Jeschkes Hotel — 2 
Bunke, Ulrich, Student, Danzig-Langfuhr, Jeschkes Hotel — 1 
Baehr, Lotte, mit Sohn, Breslau, Wikinger Hof — — — 2 
Bulle, Willy, Bankdirektor, Danzig, Baltischer Hof — — — 1 
Beussel, Kurt, mit Frau, Zossen, Ostsee-Palast — — — 2 
Birkicht, Arno, Kaufm., mit Frau, Rostock, Hubertus — — 2 
Blumberg, M., Dr. med., Arzt, mit Sohn, Berlin, Silesia — 2 
Brachrock, Karl, Stettin, Wald u. See — — — — — 1 
Briest, Friedrich, Lehrer, Berlin-Rosenthal, Steinbrückstr. 29 — 1 
Broska, Erich, Kaufm., mit Fam., Prenzlau, Moltkestr. 4 — 4 
Büttner, Fritz, Kaufm., Friedeberg i. Nm., Excelsior — — 1 
Bunk, Artur, Lehrer, mit Fam., Breslau, Bedastr. 1 — — 3 
Bunke, Ernst, Schüler, Berlin, Martha-Elsehaus — — — 1 
Buschenhagen, Paul, Rennfahrer, Berlin, Viktoria — — — 1 
Bielemann, Arthur, Kaufm., Berlin-Tempelhof, Hohenstaufen 1 
Bocker, Elisabeth, Frau, mit Fam., Wolfen, Tanneck — — 3 
Buh, Hermann, Kfm., mit Frau, Eharlottenburg, Hohenstaufen 2 
Beldring, R., Frau, mit Fam., Helbrup i. Dänin., Reichsadler 4 
Boddien, Hans, Krim -Ass., mit Fam., Stettin, Krausestr. 12 — 3 
Buth, Gotthardt, Studienrat, mit Fam., Lauenburg i. P., 
Bedastrahe 8 — — — — — — — — — — 3 
Bernstein, Jos., Student, Berlin, Irmela — — — — 1 
Brinke, Herbert, Reichenbach i. Eulengeb., Bedastr. 1 — — 1 
Bosch, Eugenie, Frau, Berlin, Hafenstr. 7 — — — — 1 
Buchholz, Hans, Architekt, Berlin, Atlantic — — — — 1 
Lharig, Magda, Frau, m. Fam., Hirschberg i. Riesengeb., Gretel 3 
Eamphausen, Elisabeth, Frau, mit Kindern, Berlin, Tip Top 3 
Chylewski, Helene, Lehrerin, Berlin-Köpenick, Kaiserpark — 1 
Eohn, Fritz, Kaufm., Berlin-Friedenau, Fürstenhof — — — 1 
Earius, Kurt, Kaufm., Finsterwalde, Atlantic — — — — 1 
Elemens, Georg, Oberspielleiter, mit Bruder, Stettin, Hubertus 2 
Dehn, Werner, Bankprokurist, Berlin, Preuhenhos — — — 1 
Dobrawohl, Kaufm., mit Frau, München, Balt. Hof — — 2 
Döpper, W., Kausm., mit Frau, Stettin, Balt. Hof — — — 2 
Dunkel, Anna, Frau, Breslau, Wikinger Hof — — — — 1 
Dannenberg, Herbert, Gerichtsassessor, Berlin, Ostsee-Palast — 1 
Dannies, Paul, Konrektor, mit Fam., Forst-L., Min Ollendeel 3 
Diederich, K., Lehrerin, m. Neff., Jarmen, Siegfried Joachim 2 
Dobrick, Georg, Dr. med., Arzt, Cottbus, Gartenstr. 16 — — 1 
Drehler, Eduard, Lehrer, mit Fam., Berlin, Eggebrechtsti-. 14 4 
Dullo, Arnold, Kaufm., Berlin, Barberina — — — — 1 
Dziemba, Marg., Berlin, Barberina — — — — — — 1 
Danielzik, Otto, Berlin, Lunkewitz — — — — — — 1 
Dittmann, Martha, mit Kind, Breslau, Königsstr. 11 — — 2 
Lberle, Hans, Dr. med., Arzt, mit Fam. u. Mädchen, Freiburg, 
Glückauf — — — — — — — — — — — 4 
Eckert, Ida, Berlin, Pommernhaus — — — — — — 1 
Edelbaum, R., Kaufm., Friedeberg, Excelsior — — — — 1 
Eggert, Fritz, Postbeamter, mit Frau, Berlin, Hartigstr. 12 — 2 
Ehrlich, Richard, Dr., Arzt, mit Fam., Arnstadt, Glückauf — 5 
Eymes, Marie, Berlin, Pommernhaus — — — — — 1 
Engel, Margarete, Mag.-Bürogehilfin, Breslau, Christl. Hospiz 1 
Engelmann, Maria, Mag.-Bürogeh., Breslau, Christl. Hospiz 1 
Eibig, Herbert, Tel.-Techn., mit Frau, Frankfurt a. O., Frieda 2 
Einert, Martha, mit Sohn, Berlin-Tegel, Königsstr. 14 — — 2 
Ehrenberg, Jngeborg, Frau, Breslau, Strandburg — — — 1 
Falk, Frau, mit Familie u. Kinderfrl,. Berlin, Eggebrechtstr. 6 4 
Fertig, Paul, Buchhalter, mit Fam., Anklam, Bedastr. 6 — 4 
Feldmann, Elsa, Breslau, Friedrichstr. 36 — — — — 1 
Feige, Wilhelm, mit Frau, Hermsdorf, Gartenstr. 13 — — 2 
Flamme, Elisabeth, Frau, Stettin, Jeschkes Hotel — — — 1 
Faibe, Otto, Kaufm., mit Frau, Görlitz, Hohenzollernhof — 2 
Felht, Ludwig, Techniker, Eharlottenburg, Europäischer Hof — 1 
Fochtmann, Hugo, Kaufm., Berlin-Schöneberg, Baltischer Hof 1 
Fahrland, Marg., Stenotypistin, Nordhausen, Lotsenstr. 38 — 1 
Fischer, Gerda, Schülerin, Berlin, Martha-Elsehaus — — 1 
Fränkel, Rolf, Architekt, mit Frau, Berlin, Schloß-Hotel — 2 
Frendy, Eduard, Berlin, Pommernhaus — — — — — 1 
Freund, Gustav, Dr., Arzt, mit Frau, Berlin, Atlantic — — 2 
Finke, Anna, Witwe, mit Tochter, Stettin, Färberstr. 2 — — 2 
Fröhlich, Hedwig, Frau, mit Kindern, Berlin, Hartigstr. 15 — 3 
Fuchs, Alwin, Kaufm., Berlin, Viktoria — — — — — 1 
Fleischer, Ida, mit Kind u. Begl., Waldenburg i. Schl., Herta 3 
Füllborn, Grete, Kontoristin, Berlin, Reichsadler — — — 1 
Frost, Erna, Frau, mit Kind, Finow i. M., Marienburg — 2 
Galier, Klara, Lehrerin, Schöneberg, Schwefel — — — 1 
Geister, Ida, Berlin-Wilmersdorf, Hohenstaufen — — — 1 
Geschefski, Max, Kaufm., Berlin, Baltischer Hof — — — 1 
Gliesche, Albert, Ober-Wassermeister, Kiel, Schmidts Hotel — 1 
Gosdinski, Georg, Kaufm., Berlin, Baltischer Hof — — — 1 
Grüneberg, Eugen, Kfm., mit Frau, Schwedt a. O., Preußenhof 2 
Glas, Erich, Rechtsanw., mit Frau, Charlottenburg, Fürstenhof 2 
Guckler, Walter, Kaufm., Berlin-Neukölln, Baltischer Hof — 1 
Genkow, Gertrud, Frau, mit Familie, Beuthen i. Schl., 
Friedenstr. 12a — — — — — — — — — 3 
Gerlich, Gertrud, Berlin-Steglitz, Hartigstr. 12 — — — 1 
Göritz, Helen, Eberswalde, Fischerstr. 17 — — — — — 1 
Göritz, Hermann, Eberswalde, Fischerstr. 17 — — — — 1 
Graf, Fritz, Apotheker, mit Frau, Nürnberg, Schloß nm Meer 2 
Graff, Horst, Charlottenburg, Atlantik — — — — — 1 
Gumpert, Sally, Kausm., mit Tochter, Berlin-Reinikendorf, 
Atlantic — — — — — — — — — — — 2 
Granzow, Anton, Lehrer, mit Frau, Frankfurt, Christl. Hospiz 2 
Grüttner, Erich, Breslau, Friedenstr. 4 — — — — — 1 
Gürtsch, Martin, Rentier, Schladebach, Schloß-Klause — — 1 
Groth, Charlotte, techn. Zeichnerin, Berlin, Meta — — — 1 
Greiner, Marta, Verkäuferin, Charlottenburg, Heysestr. 17 — 1 
»om * FLSikLir * * 
K O 2 L k 2.