
271 
Kobes, Arthur, Apotheker, Kiel, Seerings Hotel — — — 1 
Klein, Herta, Hausangest., Berlin, Ostsee-Kurheim — — — 1 
Kretschmer, Otto, Kaufm., Berlin-Pankow, Königsstra-He 11 — 1 
Kroll, Otto, Dr., Arzt, Berlin, Moltkestr. 11 — —' — — 1 
Kutterer, Valentin, Kaufm., Berlin-Friedenau, Villa Frieda — 1 
Lange, A., Dr., Facharzt, mit Frau, Kolberg, Pommernhaus 2 
Lehmann, Frieda, Frau Dr., Rechtsanw., mit Tochter, Stettin, 
Villa Gretel — — — — — — — — — — 2 
Lewinsohn, Kurt, mit Familie, Berlin, Schlosthotel — — — 3 
Liebmann, Karl, Kaufm., Neugondorf, Haus am Kurpark — 1 
Lubowski, Adele, Berlin-Wilmersdorf, Villa Margarete — — 1 
Luppas, Max, Bankbeamter, mit Frau, Berlln-Tempelhof, 
Villa Melanie — — — — — — — — — — 2 
Laufs, Richard, Fuhrherr, mit Frau, Biesdorf, Villa Klara — 1 
Leyde, Arthur, Kaufm., Berlin-Charlottenburg, Hotel Atlantic 1 
Lindner, Martin, Kaufm., Rohwein t. Sa., Hotel Atlantic — 1 
Lüthje, Hermann, Dr., Direktor, Berlin, Haackftr. 1 — — 1 
Lange, Selma, Buchhalterin, Winzig, Wiesbadener Hof — — 1 
Lachmeyer, Dr., Apotheker, Karlsruhe, Walfisch — — — 1 
v. Lagienski, Ludwig, Apotheker, mit Fam., Berlin, Rolandseck 3 
Lampe, Otto, Apotheker, Pressevertreter, Hamburg, Quisisana 1 
Lene, Leopold, Apotheker, mit Frau, Lokstedt, Villa Gertrud — 2 
Lüdke, Hanna, Stettin, Strandburg, — — — — — — 1 
Lutze, Dorothe, Sekretärin, Berlin-Lichterfelde, Achilles — — 1 
Mohling, Friedrich, Dr., Professor, B er li n- Charlottenburg, 
Pommernhaus — — — — — — — — — 1 
Marchettini, Stefan, Kaufm., mit Familie, Berlin, Dünenftr. 36 3 
Maschke, Hildegard, Kontoristin, Berlin-Lankwitz, Villa Gretel 1 
v. Mafsow, Wilhelm, Hauptm. a. D., Drosten, Villa Edith«— 1 
Matz, Bruno, Apotheker, Berlin-Hohenschönhausen, Tipp Topp 1 
Matzdorff, Ruth, Liegnitz, Villa Melanie — — — — — 1 
Mederake, Felix, Verlagsbuchhändler, mit Frau, München, 
St. Hubertus — — — — — — — — — — 2 
Menzel, Elisabeth, Frau Geheimrat, mit Tochter, Stettin, Unger 2 
Minprio, Else, Berlin-Wilmersdorf, Haus Eden — — — 1 
Minschke, Kläre, Sekretärin, Berlin, Haus Midgard — — — 1 
Mitsching, Rose, Berlin-Wilmersdorf, Haus Eden — — — 1 
Molat, Lotte, Postbeamter, Schwerin i. M., Königsstr. 29 — 1 
Marcus, R., Kaufm., Stettin, Villa Inge borg — — — — 1 
Map, Alexander, Apotheker, Dresden, St. Hubertus — — 1 
Meist, August, Apotheker, mit Familie, Mannheim, Wartburg 5 
Mengest Alfred, Dr., Apotheker, Stettin, Hotel Viktoria — — 1 
Molan, Ernst, Chefredakteur, Berlin-Charlottenburg, Favorit — 1 
Müller, Erna, Apothek., Wriezen cn O-, Villa Toni — — — 1 
Meier zu Eissen, Ilse, Wamberg, Hotel Wilhelmsruh — — 1 
Meier zu Eissen, Martin, Apotheker, Blomberg, Wilhelmsruh 1 
Matull, Elsa, Frau Kfm., mit Tochter, Stettin, Herrenbadstr. 7 2 
Meerwein, Maria, Witwe, Misdr-oy, Dornröschen — — 1 
Meyer, P., Frau, mit Familie, Berlin-Wilmersdorf, Dresd. Hof 3 
Meyer, Collins, Joachim, Dr. jur., Berlin-Halensee, Haus 
an der Sonne — — — — — — — — — 1 
Moser, Arno, Kaufm., Berlin-Charlottenburg, Villa Frieda — 1 
Ritschte, Agnes, Chem. tech., Eberswalde, Villa Fresena — 1 
Nosseck, Alfred, Kaufm., Magdeburg, Villa Elsbeth — — — 1 
Nadbyl, Eva, Frau, Berlin, Villa Gretel — — — — — 1 
Neumann, Albert, Kaufm., Berlin, Hotel Atlantic — — — 1 
Nitschke, Alfred, Fabrikbes., mit Chaufst, Cottbus, Eitel Friedrich 2 
Neumann, Alfred, Apotheker, Trauburg, Haus an der Sonne 1 
Orschler, Math., Brauereibest, mit Fr., Stanau i. M., Haiderose 2 
Orth, Edmund, Dr., Apoth., mit Familie, Hamburg, Wilhemsruh 3 
Oeser, Br. Otto, Architekt, Dresden, Bedastr. 10 — — — 1 
Pakheiser, Theodor, Dr., Facharzt, mit Familie, Heidelberg, 
Hotel Excelsior — — — — — — — — — 3 
Paug, W. P., Student, Berlin-Charlottenbudg, Hohenstaufen — 1 
Pavel, Otto, Eisenbahner, mit Familie, Oranienburg, Bis- 
marckstrahe 6— — — — — — — — — — 3 
Pieritz, Robert, Prof., Studienrat i. R., Pasewalk, Hohenstaufen 1 
Pretschke, Manfred, Dpl.-Jng., mit Gertrud, Stettin, Billevbeck 2 
Pont, Gertrud, Chauffeur, Stettin, Villa Elsbeth — — — 1 
Pretzer, Erich, Kaufm., mit Frau, Hamburg, Billa Flora — — 2 
Proennel, Otto, Direktor, mit Frau, Berlin-Grünau, Tipp Topp 2 
Paschadel, Aug., Kaufm., mit Familie, Stettin, Jeschkes Hotel 3 
Prawitz, Max, Direktor, mit Frau, Dresden, Hotel Preustenhof 2 
Panne, Eduard, Kaufm., Berlin-Lichterfelde, Wiesbadener Hof 1 
Pohl, Wilhelm, Kaufm., Sprottau, Wiesbadener Hof — — 1 
Peiser, Erich, Apotheker, Berlin, Walfisch — — — — — 1 
Pfeiffer, Otto, Apotheker, mit Familie, Berlin, Hotel Atlantic — 3 
Patschke, Gertrud, Privat., Zittau, Villa Tipp Topp — — 1 
Patschke, Fritz, Kaufm., Dresden, Villa Tipp Topp — — — 1 
Pieper, Elfriede, Kaufm., Elberfeld, Friedrichstr. 36 — — — 1 
Pützl, Lotte, Frau, Chemnitz, Hotel Viktoria — — — -— 1 
Puck, Ellen, Frau, Berlin, Hotel Atlantic — — — — — 1 
v. Quistorp, Alexander, Kaufm., Berlin, Hotel Preustenhof — 1 
Rath, Willy, Kaufm., mit Familie, Reutlingen, Hohenstaufen 3 
Reep, Käthe, Sprechstundenschwester, Halle, Siegfried Joachim 1 
Reichenberg, Frau, Stettin, Damenbadstr. la — — — — 1 
Reinecke, Wilhelm, Fabrikbes., mit Frau, Leipzig, Ostsee-Palast 2 
Reiß, Ilse, Tänzerin, Berlin, Villa Klara — — — — — 1 
Reist, Margarete, Berlin, Ostsee-Palast — — — — — 1 
Ritz, Fred, Steuersyndikus, Barmen, Kaiserpark — — — 1 
Rodmann, Friedrich, Kaufm., Berlin, Haus Schwefel — — 1 
Röhr, Meta, Berlin, Hotel Atlantic — — — — — — 1 
Rugter, Erich, mit Frau, Berlin-Charlottenburg, Villa Möwe 2 
Rare Wilhelm, Kandidat, Eberswalde, Villa Meta — — — 1 
Rehdaus, Fritz, Apotheker, mit Frau, Dresden, St. Hubertus 2 
Rojahn, Karl, Universitäts-Professor,, Halle, Haus an der Sonne 1 
Rosdorf, Karl, Apotheker, mit Frau, Breslau, Haus Möwe — 2 
Reinhold, Hanna, Frau, Magdeburg, Villa Nuhbaum — — 1 
Riemann, Eug-, Magdeburg, Villa Elsbeth— — — — — 1 
Rosenfeld, Hellmut, cand. phil., Berlin, Pommernhaus — — 1 
Richert, Georg, Landw., mit Fr., Zeheben a. O., Hohenzollernhof 2 
Rodig, Gustav, Architekt u. Baumeister, Dresden, Europ. Hof 1 
Randolf, Ulrich, Rittergutspächt., mit Fr., Hohenfelde, Seeschloh 2 
Reichelt, Anna, Frau, mit Familie, Berlin-W eitzenfee, Albrecht 3 
Reuter, Frau Dr., Generalkonsul, mit Franziska, Berlin, 
Reichsadler — — — — — — — — — — 2 
de Roche, Erich, Geschäftsführer, mit Frau, Berlin, Elisabeth 2 
Röhr, Käte, Kontoristin, Berlin, Hartigstr. 25 — — — — 1 
Rosenstiel, Kurt, Berlin, Haus am Kurpark — — — — 1 
Sefik, Achmet, Student, Berlin-Charlottenburg, Schönbrunn — 1 
Senger, Ernst, mit Frau, Oranienburg, Bismarckstr. 6 — — 2 
Shauli Behan, Seth, stud. med. dent., Berlin-Charlottenburg, 
Villa Elsbeth — — — — — — — — — — «1 
Silbermann, Ruth, Kontoristin, Liegnitz, Villa Melanie — — 1 
Sinschte, Alex, Pensionär, Brl.-Charlottenburg, Herrenbadstr. 8 1 
Smith, Oswald, Geschäftsführer, Berlin, Haus am Kurpark — 1 
Sager, R., Dr., Regierungsrat, Berlin, Haus Merkur — — 1 
Sewos, Guido, Kaufm., Stettin, Achilles — — — — — 1 
Simmel, Rich., Kaufm., Berlin-Charlottenburg, Haiderose — 1 
Seebohm, Rudolf, Apoth., mit Frau, Spantekow, Admiralstr. 3 2 
Seydel, Apotheker, Berlin, Dünenschloß — — — — — 1 
Salzmann, Heinrich, Dr., Apoth., Berlin-Wilmersdorf, Walfisch 1 
Sanitz, Günther, Apotheker, mit Frau, Grabow', Strandburg 2 
Seeling, Otto- Apoth i, mit Frau, Brl.-Wilmersdorf, Dünenschloh 2 
Sonntag, Wilh., Apotheker, mit Frau, Regensburg, Dünenschloh 2 
Sewos, Alice, Frau, mit Kind, Berlin-Wilmersdorst Achilles — 2 
Sittenfeld, Franz, Architekt, Berlin, Villa Conoordia — — 1 
Schaeffer, Charlotte, Lehrerin i. R., Stettin, Hohenzollernhof 1 
Schenk, Biene, Berlin, Villa Gretel — — — — — — 1 
Schirmer, Hans, Dipl.-Landwirt, Stettin, Eitel Friedrich — 1 
Schlesinger, Ernst, Berlin, Ostsee-Palast — — — — — 1 
Schöneweiß, Hans, Kaufm., Barmen, Bill« Frieda — — — 1 
Schröder, Elfriede, Stettin, Villa Jngeborg — — — — 1 
v. Schrötter, Heinrich, Kaufm., mit Familie, Berlin, Atlantic 4 
Schaefer, Paul. Pensionär, mit Frau, Berlin-Neukölln, Haus 
am Kurpark — — — — — — — — — — 2 
Schlegel, Ilse, Frau, mit Kind, Gößnitz, Gartenstr. 16 — — 2 
Schmidt, Rudolf, Jnsp.-Beamter, Oppeln, Villa Melanie — — 1