
ZOO 
Hansen, Friedr., Zolldirektor, Flensburg, Hotel Baltischer Hof 1 
Harter, Philipp, Oberbürgermstr., m. F., Paderborn, Preußenhof 3 
Haustochter, Erich, Kau/fm., mit Fanr., Bln.-Wilmersdorf, 
Hotel Schweriner Hof — — — — — — — — 3 
Heiser, Heinrich, Professor, Dresden, Hotel Preußenhof — — 1 
Helke, Willi, Beamter, Berlin, Hobel Schweriner Hof — — 1 
Hermann, Ernst, Fabrikant, mit Fran, Berlin, Hotel Preußenhof 2 
Herrmann, Otto, Reichsbahnb., mit Frau, Leipzig, Schwer. Hof 2 
Hochgemuth, Otto, Privatier, mit Fr., Dresden, Hohenzollernhof 2 
Höher, Emil, Gastwirt, mit Frau, Berlin, Hotel Preußenhof — 2 
Halb eck, Richard, Verleger, Berlin, Hotel Preußenhof — — 1 
Jessen, Margarethe, Röntgen-Assist., Stettin, Villa Tipp Topp 1 
Johst, Ernst, Rittergutsbes., mit Tochter, Kl. Scharlack, Hubertus 2 
Jobst, Martha, Landwirtin, mit Sohn, Königsberg, Fürstenhof 2 
Illing, Marg., Berlin, Hohenzollernhof — — — — — 1 
Jsnetel, Bruno, Berlin, Hotel Preußenhof — — — — 1 
Juschew, Walter, Amtsgerichtsrat, Jestenburg, Hotel Preußenhof 1 
Kirschke, Alfred, Stettin, Oehlkes Hotel — — — — — 1 
Krafft, Otto, Zoll-Ang., Bonlo, Schmidts Hotel — — — 1 
Kluge, Berlin, Ostsee-Palast — — — — — — — 1 
Köster, Hedwig, Frau, mit Kind, Siegen i. W., Villa Aegir — 2 
Krämer, Ludwig, Dr., Rechtsanw., mit Fr., Berlin, Hotel Jester 2 
Kraming, Herrn., Kaufm., mit Tochter, Stettin, St. Hubertus 2 
Kroner, Walter, Apothekenbes., Berlin, Hotel Atlantic — — 1 
Kronenberger, Kurt, Kaufm., Berlin, Villa Melanie — — 1 
Krsplin, Hans, Kaufm., Hamburg, Hotel Atlantic — — — 1 
Küchel, Willi, Landwirt, mit Frau, Trepin, Hotel Preußenhof 2 
Kochner, Walter, Berlin, Hotel Elisabeth — — — — — 1 
Kelle, Walter, Privatmann, mit Frau, Dessau, Kühle Quelle — 2 
Kerstens, Paul, Verlagsdirektor, mit Fam., Berlin, Baltisch. Hos 3 
o. Kleist, Lis, Major a. D., mit Fr., Drenow, Hotel Preußenhof 2 
Kolbe, Earl, Kapitän, mit Frau, Hamburg, Jeschkes Hotel — 2 
Komki, Alexander, Fabrikant, Bln.-Friedenau, Hotel Preußenhof 1 
Kramsel, Marg., Frau Dr., Buderose, Hohenzollernhof — — 1 
Krause, Elfriede, Roskow, Hotel Schweriner Hos — — — 1 
Leopold, Marg., Beuthen, Schmidts Hotel — — — — 1 
v. Loutzkoy, Boris, Dipl.-Jng,, mit Frau, Berlin, Hotel Atlantic 2 
Lehmann, Max, Dr. jur., Rechtsanw., mit Fam., Stettin, Gretel 3 
Leistuer, Dr., Revisionsbe-amter, Bln.-Fehlend., Maria Theresia 1 
Lippold, Paul, Rentier, mit Frau, Potsdam, St. Hubertus — 2 
Lutter, Martin, Kaufm., mit Fam., Berlin, Park-Hotel — — 3 
Loefer, Karl, Kaufm., mit Frau, Berlin, Hotel Atlantic — — 2 
Lüdke, Willy, Bankbeamter, mit Frau, Bln.-Lankwitz, Bedastr. 2 2 
Liebenow, Hubert, Studienrat, mit Frau, Stettin, Wikinger Hof 2 
Lorenz, Elisabeth, Mückenberg, Hotel Schweriner Hof — — 1 
Lunow, Traute, Haustocht., Sälen b. Ratzeburg, Schweriner Hof 1 
TNank, Joh., Dresden^ Villa Azurea — — — — — — 1 
Margulies, Max, Dr., Oberarzt, mit Frau, Berlin, Hotel Viktoria 2 
Martini, Irene, Hann.-Münden, Villa Gretel — — — — 1 
Mascum, Kurt, Kaufm., mit Fam., Stettin, Villa Astrid — — 5 
Meyer, Hedwig, Ww., Berlin-Neukölln, Privatstr. 13 — — 1 
Mosner, Ellen, Schauspielerin, Stettin, Hotel Jester — — 1 
v. d. Mülbe, Otto, Dr. jur., Oberleutm, Berlin, Pens. Billerbeck 1 
Musberg, Anna, Schwester, Soest, Pommernhaus — — — 1 
Miericke, August, Kreiskämmerer i. R., Nauen, Kurparkstr. 14 1 
Maginitzki, Lotte, Halle a. S., Hotel Mirstenhof — — — 1 
Müller, Lange, Crista, Fr., mit Sohn, Viersadten, Preußenhof 2 
Malbrank, Paul, Stettin, Hotel Preußenhof — — — — 1 
Mallow, Gerda, Stütze, ? Kühle Quelle — — — 1 
v. Meyer, Eugen, Kaufm., Berlin, Hotel Preußenhof — — 1 
Milan, Fioradante, Brah, Sano, Hotel Westend — — — 1 
Müller, Otto, Gastwirt, Berlin, Hotel Preußenhof — — — 1 
Müller, Gerhard, Kaufm., mit Frau, Berlin, Wikinger Hof — 2 
zu Münster, Hans-Wulfhard, Graf, Oberleutn. a. D., Berlin, 
Wikinger Hof — — — — — — — ,— — — 1 
Ratztat, Lina, Fulda, Villa Gretel — — — — — — 1 
Nicolai, Wilhelm, Rittergutsbes., mit Frau, Wulkow, Fremden 
heim Mehl — — — — — — — — — — 2 
Neupert, Max, Kaufm., Blm-Charlottenburg, Villa Lotte —, 1 
Noack, Georg, Rechtsanw., mit Fr., Forst i. L., Villa Tipp Topp 2 
Otto, Georg, Handlungsgeh., Treptow, Oehlkes Hotel — — 1 
Oberhausen, Erich, Dentist, Königsberg, Hotel Fürstenhof — 1 
Ollerdissen, Julius, Kaufm., Berlin, Soeschloh — — — — 1 
Oppenfeld, Landwirt, Ritzerow, Ostsee-Palast — — — — 1 
Onaß, Bruno, Maler, Berlin, Bollwerk 17 — — — — 1 
Pratsch, Hildegard, Potsdam, Hotel Schweriner Hof — — 1 
Pape, Hermann, Lehrer, Bad Salzgitter, Hot. Schweriner Hof 1 
Peemllller, Karl, Studienrat, Zoppot, Jeschkes Hotel — — 1 
Perkowski, Helene, Berlin-Charlottenburg, Hotel Preußenhof — 1 
Pohl, Reinhard, Jng., mit Frau, Leipzig, Hotel Preußenhof — 2 
Pohl, Felix, Kaufm., Leipzig, Jeschkes Hotel — — — — 1 
Pokrand, Alfred, Dr., Polizei-Schulrat, mit Frau, Königsberg, 
Hotel Preußenhof — — — — — — — — — 2 
Pindro, David, Kaufm., Berlin, Hohenzollernhof — — — 1 
Pape, Otto Friedrich, Kunstmaler, Architekt, Berlin, Barbarossa 1 
Peegor, Wilhelm, Reg.-Baumeister, Berlin, Hotel Atlantic — 1 
Pieper, Alois, Arzt, Hellstedt i. Südharz, Schloß-Hotel — — 1 
Pietskowski, Dr., Amtsgerichtsrat, Oppeln, Park-Horel — — 1 
Pretschke, Manfred, Dipl.-Jng., mit Fr., Stettin, Pens. Billerbeck 2 
Peglau, Frau, mit Tochter, Berlin, Hohenzollernhof — — 2 
Plenard, E., Gewerbeschülerin, Berlin, Hotel Fürstenhof — — 1 
Peters, Johannes, Jng., Prokurist, Stettin, Jeschkes Hotel — 1 
Ploghar, Johann, Dr., Richter a. D., Prag, Hotel Preußenhof 1 
Radmann, Dr., Zahnarzt, Wolgast, Wikinger Hof — — — 1 
Ratz, Wilhelm, Fabrikant, Vergstadt, Hotel Preußenhof — — 1 
v. Ratziwill, Franz, Kfm., mit Frau, Stettin, Hobel Preußenhof 2 
Reich, Bruno, Dr., Arzt, Neumünster, Hotel Schweriner Hof 1 
Reich, Theresia, Berlin, Swinemünder Hof — — — — 1 
Rekinky, Kurt, Schechnen, Hotel Preußenhof — — — — 1 
Renter, Karl, Kaufm., Stettin, Hotel Preußenhof — — — 1 
Richter, Johann, Kaufm., Berlin, Hotel Preußenhof — — 1 
Riegel, Max, Optiker, Berlin, Hotel Schweriner Hof — — 1 
Rintisch, Herm., Privatier, mit Frau, Potsdam, Schweriner Hof 2 
Rösun, Georg, Bauunternehm., m. Fr., Weißstem, Wikinger Hof 2 
Rische, Robert, Schmollen, Hobel Preußenhof — — — — 1 
Rubens, H., Buchhalber, Berlin-Steglitz, Hotel Schweriner Hof 1 
Rüne, Werner, Dipl.-Landwirt, Stettin, Hotel Preußenhof — 1 
Rode, Karl, Dr., mit Fam., Central-Hotel — — — — 3 
Rübesam, Paul, Maj. a. D., Dirnschin, Kr. Kolberg, Preußenhof 1 
Randelpho, Gerhardt, Dipl.-Landw., Königsberg, Jeschkes Hotel 1 
Range, August, Fuhrmann, mit Frau, Hönow, Hot. Preußenhof 2 
Reich, Willi, Lehrer, mit Frau, Werder, Jeschkes Hotel — — 2 
Reysche, Gustav, Oberingen., Dortmund, Hotel Preußenhof — 1 
Richer, Richard, Rentner, mit Frau, Abschreunthen, Preußenhof 2 
Ro-esler, Lucie, Berlin«-Neukölln, Hotel Schweriner Hof — — 1 
Roßmann, Sekretärin, Bln.-Lichtenderg, Hotel Preußenhof 1 
Saab, Ellen, Dresden, Bartenstein, Jeschkes Hotel — — — 1 
Seelbinder, Fritz, Krafts., mit Frau, Berlin, Hobel Schwer. Hof 2 
Siegmund, Rich., Polizeioffiz., Waldenburg, Wikinger Hof — 1 
Singmann, Alfred, Dipl-Jng., mit Frau, Berlin, Jefchkes Hot. 2 
Süßmann, Joh., Reichsbahn-Angest., Steingrift, Schwer. Hof 1 
Siggel, Alfred, Dr., Berlin, Hotel Fürstenhof — — — — 1 
Sunlinger, Walter, Opernsänger, Berlin, Hohenzollernhof — 1 
Seifarth, Frdr. Const., Dr., Referend., Kl. Kauer, Hot. Elisabeth 1 
Skuhra, Hans, Kaufm., mit Frau, Berlin, Dornröschen — — 2 
Sorko, Emil, Kaufm., Amsterdam, St. Hubertus — — — 1 
Siedmann, Elfriede, Frau, Liegnitz, Beatus ille — — — 1 
Seith, Wolfgang, Dr., Privatdozent, mit Frau, Schweriner Hof 1 
Siegmund, Martha, Ww., mit Rudolf, Bautzen, Preußenhof 2 
Schmidt, Hellerau, Karl, Fabrikdir., m. Fr., Dresden, Preußenh. 2 
Schmidt, Paul, Kraftf., Greifswald, Oehlkes Hotel — 1 
Schneider, Franz, Studienrat, Berlin-Steglitz, Hotel Preußenhof 1 
Schramm, Heinz, Student, Zürich, Schweriner Hof — — — 1 
Schulz, Franz, Justizsekr., Berlin, Oehlkes Hobel — — — 1 
Schulz, Paul, Kaufm., mit Frau, Stettin, Jeschkes Hotel — — 2 
Schulz, Jeiny, Frau, Gräfin, Berlin, Hotel Preußenhof — — 1